Ildikó Tóth

UX Designer



I am a code-savvy, detail-oriented designer in Portland, OR. Pivoting my career to the full spectrum of UX, I am excited to bring my previous experience with engineering together with my more recent UX work to positively transform how users interact with the world around them.

CONTACT

J 703.597.8004

in linkedin.com/in/ildikototh

SKILLS

VISUAL

Adobe(Ps, II,Id)

Axure

Balsamia

Figma

InVision

Sketch

RESEARCH

A/B Testing

Card Sort

Heuristic Analysis

Survey Design

Usability Testing

DEVELOPMENT

Github

HTML / CSS

JavaScript / jQuery

Python / C# / SQL

PRESENTATION

Camtasia

Draw.io

iMovie

Keynote /Powerpoint

PERSONAL

Certified Agile Product Owner
Airbnb Host and Business Owner
Fluent in French and Hungarian
Mazamas Mountaineering Club
Member

EXPERIENCE

Code for Portland - UX Design Lead

Oct 2018 - Current

Social media scraper: Researching Clackamas County public health professionals' pain points in collecting social media messages relating to infectious diseases. Designing for those needs using data collected from surveys, interviews, workshops, and usability tests. Working with developers to hand off requirements and iterate through designs.

Bloc.io - UX Design Apprentice

Sept 2017 - Oct 2018

Copilot: Designed a mobile parking & navigation app that relays street parking availability. Completed work employing generative research, user flows, usability/preference tests, a design system, and UI design.

Cirrus: Conducted market assessment of cloud storage services. Iterated from wireframes to high-fidelity mockups using results from remote and in-person usability tests.

Intel - Business Analyst + Product Owner

Jul 2015 - Jan 2017

Retailer onboarding: Redesigned sign-up process to include company search shortcut and a location-smart address input. Developed storyboards, user stories and flows for cross-functional groups and external design agencies. Improved and reduced data entry + exit rates.

Channel member hierarchy: Reorganized a multi-tiered reward system of 500k members. Visually simplified complex data to decision makers.

Intel - Automation Software Engineer

Jul 2011 - Jan 2015

Scheduler solution design: Worked to support process changes to semiconductor manufacturing R&D via material delivery. Conducted user interviews, designed, tested and developed through rapid iteration.

EDUCATION

Stanford University & Portland State University 2012 - 2014 HCI & Computer Science Courses GPA: 3.8/4

Syracuse University 2006 - 2010

BA Graphic Design + Math. Minor in IT GPA: 3.93/4